Finding Aid for the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection LSC.0100
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Author Identified
  - Nichols, William I. (?) 1 autograph. (Box 5)
    Removed from: Orioli, G., Adventures of a bookseller. Z340 069A1 1938
  - Nin, Anaïs, 1903-1977 (Box 284, 287)
    - Un Vie, Une Oeuvre - French radio broadcast relating to Nin., 1991 12 December.; (1 cassette [in French]). (Box 287, Folder 5)
      France-Culture radio broadcast on 12 December 1991.
      Gift of Noel Riley Fitch.
      Card under Nin, Anais--material relating to.
    - 4 postcards and 2 letters to Edward Gilbert., 1951-1959.; (12 items, 9pp.). (Box 284, Folder 7)
      re selling Nin's books. Includes 6 receipts for purchases, and promo of A Spy in the House of Love.
      Part of Nin and Miller archive from Gibert's and the Satyr shops.
    - Letter [typescript, signed] to Miss Eckhard re publishing., ca. 1947.; (1 item, 1p.). (Box 287, Folder 2)
      Purchase Jeff Weber.
      Card under Nin, Anaïs--correspondence.
  - Nixon, Richard Milhouse. Invitation to inauguration., 1973. (Box 188, Folder 3)
  - Normanby, Constantine Henry Phipps, 1st marquis of, 1797-1863. Correspondence. 5 items. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Norton, Hon. Mrs. Caroline (Sheridan), 1808-1877. Correspondence, signed, to various persons. 47 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    Letter to Sir Archibald Alison, undated. Letter to William Charles Macready, undated. Letter to Henry Colburn, 1839 October 20. Letter to "Dear Mr. Ayle?," regarding John M. Kemble, undated. 1 letter to Smith, Elder & Co., 1831 November 4. 2 letters to Abraham Hayward, 1844 March 28; circa 1837. 1 letter to Anna Maria Hall, undated. 1 letter to Lady Catherine Stepney, undated. 1 letter to John William Parker, 1858 March 4. 1 letter to Jerrold Douglas, 1846. Another Copy. 1 reel 35 mm negative microfilm. 1 letter to Clarkson Stanfield, 1843.
  - Norton, Lawrence. 13 letters to Oliver Neighbor and printed invitation to Morton's 75th birthday., 1964-1979.; (14 items, 19pp.). (Box 281, Folder 8)
    Letters re Igor Stravinsky and California music scene.
  - Nye, Edgar Wilson, 1850-1896. Correspondence. 9 items. Holograph. (Box 32)
    Nye was the noted American humorist known as Bill Nye. Another copy. Various items. 1 reel 35mm negative microfilm.
  - O'Casey, Sean, 1880-1964. Correspondence. Circa 1961 6 items. Holograph. (Box 12)
    3 letters to Leslie Herbert Daiken, 1961.
  - O'Connell, Daniel. 3 Letters to William Tait., 1832-1835. (Box 192, Folder 20)
  - O'Flaherty, Liam, 1896-1984. Darkness, a tragedy in three acts. London. E. Archer. 1926 (Box 19)
    Gift: Harry Ruby, 1952 January 7.
    1) Typescript draft. 2) Corrected galley proof. 3) Page proofs.
  - O'Flaherty, Liam, 1896-1984. Notebook. Circa 30 pages. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Office of Scientific Personnel, et al. Source Book, conference on predoctoral education in the U.S., 1969 August. (Box 187, Folder 4)
  - Ogburn, Cal. Fate of Faquita Rivera. undated 299 pages. Typescript, bound. (Box 13)
    Purchased: Dawson, 1953 September 16.
    Original novel set in Southern California.
  - Ord, Edward Otho Cresap, 1818-1883. To Brigadier General J. B. McPherson, Head Quarters, Corinth, Mississippi. 1862 September 11 1 p. Letter signed. (Box 31)
    General Order No. 14 relative to the procedure of detailing troops from one command to another, issued by command of Ord, major general commanding, over the signature of P. Ord, major and assistant adjutant general of volunteers.
  - Owen, Robert Dale, 1800-1877. To the Graphic Co., [New York]. 1874 October 1 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Request for copies of the Graphic and copy of his article in a London paper. Over Owen's holograph is written "Will be published supplement Saturday. D.H."
  - Owens, Elizabeth. Letter to "Dear Brother & Sister.", 1863. (Box 194, Folder 9)
    Dated May 17, 1863, post location unknown.
  - Pacific Telephone and Telegraph. Station development figures for Mr. Titus [typescript carbon]., 1926 August.; (1 item, 5pp.). (Box 285, Folder 17)
    Figures for population and station connections for 1881-1926, with estimates to 1931.
  - Palfrey, John Gorham, 1796-1881. To Reverend D. Pierce, Boston. 1845 May 7 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Information asked by historian Palfrey of the Congregational Charitable Society concerning widows and their residences. List of widows includes the names Goddard, Hathorne, Niles, and Stowe.
  - Palmer, Edward. Description of a journey. circa 1869 9 leaves. A. ms. S. (Box 8)
    Pickwick, 1954 February 15.
    Description of a journey from Fort Yuma, California to the coast of Lower California, starting from Port Isabella in 1869.
  - Palmer family business papers, 1828-1867. Ca. 80 pieces. (Box 7)
    Gift: Ernst V. Sutton, Sept., 1955.
    Consisting of the stocks, accounts, property indentures and other agreements of George Palmer and the checks of Everard Palmer, relating to their finances and business in Buffalo and Palmyra, New York.
  - Paramount Unified School District. Emergency School Aid Application., 1973.; (Copy). (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Pardoe, Julia, 1806-1862. Correspondence, signed, to various persons. 16 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    1 letter to Lady Catherine Stepney, undated. 1 letter to Anna Maria Hall, 1844 July 30.
  - Parker, Irene. Early California., n.d. (Box 190, Folder 4)
    Holograph notes.
  - Parker, Sir Gilbert, bart., 1862-1932. Letters, signed, to Mrs. [Alice] Stuart-Wortley [wife of Charles Beiby Stuart-Wortley]. London. 1910 July 21 and 24 2 letters, holograph. (Box 11)
    Manuscripts removed from Sir Gilbert Parker, Embers, London, 1908.
    With these: holograph card "With Sir Gilbert Parker's compliments," and form letter of 1915 June 11.
  - Patterson, William, 1790-1868. To H[ezekiah] Niles, Baltimore, Maryland. 1833 March 18 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning the threatened cessation of publication of Niles' Register, and the issue of the tariff.
  - Payson, Eliot. To Artimas Hale, Morrisville, [New York]. 1833 March 19 3 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning the affairs of a schoolteacher, the feelings of local citizens concerning the Tariff of 1833, S.C.'s nullification, and legislature of the state, including temperance and abolition of imprisonment for debt.
  - Peacock, Thomas Love, 1785-1866. Correspondence. 1 folder. (Box 29)
  - Pearlberg, Irving. You can see Catalina, by Irv Pearlberg. Illustrations by Lee Mishkin with an introduction by Fred Beck and O. K. Barnes. The hilarious story of UCLA. [Los Angeles]. 1949 19 leaves. 28 cm. Typescript with corrections. (Box 17)
    Published in Los Angeles (?), 1949. Chapter 3 is missing. There are two copies (original and carbon) of Chapter 4. Also includes four of the original illustrations by Mishkin, and three cartoons he did for the UCLA Daily Bruin.
  - Pearlberg, Irving. You can see Catalina, by Irv Pearlberg. Illustrations by Lee Mishkin. 7 items. Original pen and ink drawings. Shelved oversize. (Box 23)
  - Peattie, Donald C. Letter to Harry Zollars., 1934 11 April.; (1 item, 2pp. [holograph]). (Box 286, Folder 5)
    re the Wunderkinder in literature.
    Purchase: Doris Harris.
  - Pemberton, Sir Max, 1863-1950. Correspondence. 19 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Pennington, Alexander C.M., 1811-1867. To General R.K. Call, Newark, New Jersey. 1840 August 18 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning the Tippecaneo Club and local Whig party meetings of Newark. Letterhead of candidate William Henry Harrison and the Log Cabin-Cider motif.
  - Perkins, Edith (Forbes). 1 als nd. (Box 7)
    Removed from the Perkins' letters and journals, 1908-1925.
  - Perles, Alfred. Letters, short biography [1p. typecript] and material re Henry Miller., ca. 1962.; (3 items, 11pp.). (Box 283, Folder 6)
    2 letters to "Frank" and reprint of Henry Miller's Banned Books by Perles. Explanitory note from "Frank" on material.
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943. Correspondence to Mrs. J. Morris Slemons. 1933-1935 2 items. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Philips, Francis Charles, 1849-1921. Correspondence. 2 items. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Phillips, Stephen, 1868-1915. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 15)
  - Phillpotts, Eden, 1862-1960. 29 letters to Maurice Buxton Forman., 1910-1951.; (79+ items, approximately 46pp. [holograph]). (Box 283, Folder 1)
    15 without envelopes, 4 envelopes without letters.
    - 10 letters [8 holograph, 2 typescript], 14 postcards, 1 X-Mas card., 1924-1945.; (26 items, 11pp.). (Box 283, Folder 2)
      Letters to Phillpotts from others (1924-1930), postcards to Forman (1924-1945), card (1938).
  - Pico, Catalina papers. 1887 November 15 1 piece. (Box 8)
    Copy of deed granted by Catalina and Romulo Pico to Porter land and Water Company for certain water rights on lands of Rancho Ex-Misi=n de San Fernando.
  - Pickersgill, Henry William, 1782-1875. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 12)
  - Pierson, Job, 1791-1860. Letters to Levi Woodbury, Secretary of the Navy, Washington. and to F[rancis P[reston] Blair, Washington. 1833 January 14 and 1834 December 1 (Box 16)
    Inquiry to Woodbury concerning the petition and application on the behalf of George Jones as midshipman. An order to Blair for the Congressional Globe for some New York men.
  - Pinkney, William. Sermon manuscript and other items. (Box 5)
    Removed from: Hutton, O. William Pinkney. BX 5995 P65H9
    1 manuscript of sermon. 1 tl regarding sermon. 1 clipping regarding sermon. 1 calling card. 1 facsimile Pinkney crest. 1 bookplate (Frank Leslie Pleadwell).
  - Pitkin, Timothy, 1766-1847. To Reverend Dr. Sprague, Utica, New York. 1841 November 11 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Pitkin, former Representative from New York, sends some autographs and papers from Lewis J. Cist.
  - Platt, Jonas, 1769-1834. Correspondence and papers. 1794-1822 6 pieces. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Platt, county and state officer, New York, writes concerning naval appointments, court cases, and personal finances.
  - Pleasonton, Augusts James, 1808-1892. To Colonel Reah Frarer, Philadelphia. 1840 June 7 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
  - Pollack, Sir Fredrick, 1845-1937. Letter to Thomas (later Sir Thomas) Barclay., 1895 28 March.; (1 item, 3pp.). (Box 282, Folder 6)
    re upcoming meeting of the Franco-Scottich Society in Paris.
    Gift of Robert Pepper.
  - Pope, Alexander, 1763-1835. Correspondence to E. Dubois. 1830 January 8 1 item. Holograph. (Box 17)
    Mentions Charles Mathews.
  - Porreta, Philip P. California's Lost Mission, San Pedro y San Pablo de Bicuner - Manuscript., 1981 17 July.; (1 item, 77pp.). (Box 285, Folder 19)
    Typescript, copy, signed.
  - Pound, Ezra Loomis, 1885-1972 (Box 289, Folder 12, 14-15)
    - Letter to Auguste Fruge., 1948 13 September.; (1 item, 1p.). (Box 289, Folder 12)
      re possible future projects.
      Card under Pound, Ezra.
    - [Pound, Ezra Loomis, 1885-1972]. Letter from Homer L. Pound to Reverend C.C. Bubb., 1918 5 August.; (1 item, 1p. [typescript, signed]). (Box 289, Folder 13)
      re publication of an EP manuscript.
      Purchase: Doris Harris(?)
      Card under Pound, Ezra--correspondence.
    - Correspondence & printed material., 1947-1955.; (38 items, 21pp.). (Box 289, Folder 14)
      11 postcards (5 blank), 21 letters & 12 envelopes [holograph and typescript], 4pp. (no.1, 5-8).
      Gift of John Berry.
    - Letters., 1933.; (8 items, 8pp.). (Box 289, Folder 15)
      6 letters [typescript, 1 signed, 4 initialed only] and one fragment.
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1906-2001. R. A. in Los Angeles. Los Angeles. 1964 4 leaves. 28 cm. Typescript (carbon). (Box 18)
    Publishing in "Richard Aldington: an intimate portrait," edited by Alister Kershaw and Frederic- Jacques Temple, Carbondale and Edwardsville, Southern Illlinois Unversity Press, 1965, pages 106-109. With this, a letter (carbon) dated 1964 April 22 from Powell to Harry T. Moore, sending him this piece on Aldington.
  - Prah, Kwesi K. Johannes Jacobus Eliza Capitein (1717-1747)., n.d.; (Typescript, photocopy). (Box 201, Folder 10)
  - Pratt, Zadock, 1790-1871. Correspondence. 1838-1859 6 letters. (Box 32)
  - Prentiss, John Holmes, 1784-1861. Correspondence. 1834-1840 3 letters. Holograph signed. (Box 32)
  - Proctor, Edna Dean, 1829-1923. Correspondence, holograph signed, to Fred W. Hopkins. Peoria, Illinois. 1899 October 31. 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Proffit, George H., 1807-1847. To various persons. Circa 1841 4 letters. Holograph signed. (Box 10)
    Two letters are undated. Includes one letter 1841 March 5 to Abel Parker Upshur, Secretary of the Navy.
  - Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Letter and picture., (2 items, 1p. [holograph, in Italian]). (Box 288, Folder 5)
    Letter addressed to Tonino re request for visit. With English translation.
    Purchase[?].
    Card under Puccini, Giacomo--letters.
  - Putnam, George Haven, 1844-1930. To David Robinson, New York. 1927 February 4 2 p. Typed letter signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning Publisher Putnam's political loyalties as an Anti-slavery Republican, as an opponent of James G. Blaine in 1884, and as a personal friend of Grover Cleveland.
  - Putnam, Herbert, 1861-1955. Letter, signed, to Lawrence Clark Powell. Washington. 1950 June 7 1 p. (Box 5)
    Herbert Putnam was a former Librarian of Congress.
  - Quimby, John. History of San Diego County. 1948 1 folder. Typescript. (Box 19)
  - Rackham, Arthur, 1867-1939. Correspondence and bibliography. 1 folder. (Box 25)
    Gift: Pickwick Bookshop.
  - Ramsay, Thomas. To Henry O'Reilly. 1831 February 19 3 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning political machinations and spoils among the Jacksonians in Albany, New York. There is mention of Edwin Croswell and William L. Marcy, members of the "Albany Regency "which dominated the state in the 1830s.
  - Randall, Samuel Jackson, 1828-1890. Correspondence. 1884-1889 3 letters and envelopes. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    A letter to Walker H. French, Berwyn, Pennsylvania, 1884 November 13, expressing rejoicing over the election of Grover Cleveland and asserting that Randall has no thought of obtaining appointment by Cleveland. A letter to Mrs. Flora G. Moulton, Washington, 1884 April 18 and a letter to Mr. John Burt, Philadelphia, 1889 August 3, both of which are responses for autographs by Randall, Speaker of the House.
  - Randolph, Theodore Fritz, 1826-1883. Letter to D.P. Child, Esq., 1877 1 December.; (1 item, 1p. [holograph]). (Box 282, Folder 14)
    In holograph at top: Senate Chamber. Reply to request for autograph.
  - Ranee of Sarawak. 1 tls to Cameron Rogers. 1937 Dec 7 (Box 5)
  - Reach, Angus Bethune, 1821-1856. Correspondence. 4 items. Holograph. (Box 19)
    Another copy. 1 reel 35 mm negative microfilm #04236. 1 letter to George Cruikshank, undated. Cruikshank's notes appear on the reverse of the letter.
  - Read, Opie Percival, 1852-1939. Correspondence. 1886, 1895, 1896 3 items. Holograph. (Box 25)
    2 letters to "My dear George," 1895 September 16 and 1896 February 24. 1 letter or draft to "My dear Sir," 1886 October 28.
  - Reed, Isaac, 1742-1807. Diaries and notebooks. 1762-1807 5 folders containing circa 350 leaves. (Box 35)
    Research Grant Funds: Dr. Claude Jones, editor of "Isaac Reed Diaries - 1762-1804," published: Berkeley, University of California, 1946.
    Negative photocopies of 25 volumes of diaries kept by the 18th century English drama editor, journalist, and solicitor of Staple Inn. Reed writes briefly of his daily occupations: dining out, tea, church, and almost nightly visits to the theatre, in London and out. Titles of plays are noted, together with names of men connected with the performances.
  - Reeves, Mrs. Helen Buckingham (Mathers), 1853-1920. Correspondence. 19 items. Holograph. (Box 27)
    Mrs. Reeves wrote under the name "Helen Mathers."
  - Calling card of Elisbeth Reichelt, nee Albrecht, pictures and 2 newspaper articles., 1960; (5 items, 2pp.). (Box 284, Folder 16)
    Articles re Christmas cards and Stammbuchen [German and English].
  - Reid, Mayne, 1818-1883. The naturalist in Siluria. Preface. Circa 1880 5 leaves. 33. 5 cm. Holograph manuscript. (Box 30)
    "The naturalist in Siluria" was first published by Sonnenscheim & Co., London, 1889.
  - Reid, Whitelaw, 1837-1912. Correspondence. 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Renouard, Antoine Augustin, 1765-1853. Letter to M. le Chevalier Mortara., 1827 7 March.; (1 item, 2pp. [holograph, signed]). (Box 281, Folder 9)
    Renouard's seal still attached.
    Purchased: E.K. Schreiber.
    - Renouard, Ant. Aug. (Antoine Augustin), 1765-1853. Autograph letter. Paris., 7 March 1827.; (Signed, 2pp., with integral address, 204 × 104mm. - with Renouard's monogrammed seal). (Box 281, Folder 9)
      Renouard addresses the letter to M. le Chevalier Mortara, at the Hotel Meurice, thanking him for having filled a lacuna in his Aldine collection.
  - Reston, John, To Hezekiah Niles, Baltimore. 1829 March 28 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 10)
  - Revoil, Georges. Mission G. Revoil, 1880-81., n.d.; (Notebook, bound). (Box 192, Folder 1)
    On Somalis tribe in East Africa.
  - Rexroth, Kenneth, 1905- (Box 193, 286, 289)
    - "Floating" - poem in American Poetry Review., 1982.; (1 item, p.48). (Box 193, Folder 9)
      Gift of New Directions.
      Card under Rexroth, Kenneth.
    - 3 letters and postcard to Jake Zeitlin., 1931-1948.; (4 items, 3pp. [holograph]). (Box 286, Folder 4)
      2 letters and postcard from KR (1948), one from Audree Rexroth (1931).
      Purchase: Jeff Weber Card also under Zeitlin, Jake--letters from KR.
    - Journal - Plein Chant (no.24)., 1985.; (1 item [in French]). (Box 289, Folder 4)
      Entire issue devoted to Kenneth Rexroth.
      Card under K. Rexroth.
  - Rhey, John. Correspondence. Harrisburgh, Pennsylvania. 1852 January 11 3 pp. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Rhey, nominated Speaker of the State Assembly, writes of that event and of his family, the approaching reception for Louis Kossuth, and the incoming and outgoing governors of the state.
  - Richardson, Sir Benjamin Ward. 1 als. 1888 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Ricahrson, Sir B. W., The son of a star. PR 5226 Rs
  - Richardson, William Adams, 1821-1896. To Captain John Farmer, Washington. 1874 March 14 1 p. letter signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning payment on claim of Widow of Chief Engineer Walter Scott of Revenue Marine Service by Richardson, Secretary of the Treasury.
  - Rideout, Henry Milner, 1877-1927. Correspondence to Herman Whitaker, Saint Andrews, New Brunsick, Canada. 1909 September 4 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Rimbaud, Arthur, 1854-1891. A Season in Hell., n.d.; (34 items, 70pp.). (Box 287, Folder 7)
    Pencil mock-up, proofs galleys, notes, outline, circular, greeting card, paper sample.
    Purchase: Minkoff.
  - Rinehart, Stanley Marshall, 1897-1969. Telegram to Pat Hunt's Book Shop, Hollywood, California. New York. 1933, May 11 1 item. (Box 5)
    Removed from Brinig's The Flutter of an Eyelid, collection PS 3503/ B769f.
  - Rinehart, of the publishing firm of Farrar & Rinehart, telegrams that Myron Brinig's The Flutter of an Eyelid (New York, Farrar & Rinehart, c1933) is being withdrawn, and to remove all copies. (Box 5)
  - Ripert, Emile. 1 als 1920 (Box 5)
    Removed from Ripert, Emile. Renaissance provencale.
  - Ripley, ? To General Gideon Johnson Pillow, Nashville [?]. 1849 March 8 3 pp. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
    A discussion of local Nashville and Tennessee politics with personal references to Pillow's family and friends.
  - Ripley, George, 1802-1880. To Benson J. Lossing, New York. 1864 August 15 2 pp. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Reformer and scholar Ripley writes from his office with the New York Tribune to inquire of historian Lossing about a position at Vassar for a military surgeon friend.
  - Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796. Letter to Thomas Wharton and one other piece. Circa 1777 March 19 2 pieces. (Box 10)
    Letter to Wharton, Governor of Pennsylvania, 1777-1778, from Rittenhouse, State Treasurer, concerning draft of funds by State House of Assembly.
  - Robb, John, To Samuel Smith, Washington. 1833 July 19 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 10)
    Concerning the dismissal of Smith's nephew G.C.Stiles from a post in the federal government.
  - Robbins, Asher, 1757-1845. To [Samuel Lewis] Southard, Newport, Rhode Island. 1827 May 12 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 10)
    Requesting an appointment by Southard, Secretary of the Navy, for the son of Lt. William Taylor, as midshipman.
  - Robeson, Paul, 1898-1976. Correspondence to Dorothy La Pelle. undated. 1 item. Holograph. With envelope. (Box 17)
  - Robins, Elizabeth, 1862-1952. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 12)
  - Robinson, Orville, 1801-1882. To L[uther] Bradish, [Albany]. 1837 April 21 1 p. holograph signed. (Box 10)
    Concerning stock investments involving John Jacob Astor.
  - Robinson, Sir John Richard, 1828-1903. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Rochefort, H[enri?]. Letter to Mon Cher Leon., n.d.; (1 item, 1p. [holograph, in French]). (Box 282, Folder 16)
    Writing indecipherable.
  - Rockefeller, John Davison, 1839-1937. Letters to Charles L. Colby. 1884 February 13 and 21 2 letters. Holograph signed. (Box 10)
    Concerning investments by both men in the Wisconsin Central Railroad, of which Colby was President.
  - Rodin, Auguste, 1840-1917. Letter to Mister Vacquerie., 1889 16 October.; (1 item, 1p. [holograph, in French]). (Box 288, Folder 4)
    Letter of introduction for M. Loizeau, artist friend of Victor Hugo. With English translation.
    Purchase(?).
    Card under Rodin, Auguste--letters.
  - Rodman, Gilbert, To J. W. Reckless (?), Washington. 1833 November 4 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 10)
    Concerning U.S. internal revenue law relative to the transportation of merchandise through Perth Amboy, Middlesex County, New Jersey.
  - Rogerson, Monsignor J. S. Some account of the later moments of the Reverend Frank Mahony ("Father Prout") written by his friend, the priest who attended him. 1877 April 23 1 p. l., 14 leaves. 17.5 x 22.5 cm. Holograph. (Box 17)
    An account of the last days of Francis Sylvester Mahony (1804-1866). Not known if published.
  - Rohmer, Eric, 1920-2010 and Claude Chabrol. Hitchcock. undated. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Rolle, Andrew F. Riviera path... (Box 7)
    For complete description, see this entry in relative index.
  - Romer, Isabella F. Correspondence. 3 items. (Box 29)
  - Rolle, Andrew F. An American in California. undated Circa 250 pages typescript and proof copies. (Box 33)
    180 pages, numbered, and circa 25 pages, unnumbered, typescript with holograph corrections. Together with corrected first proof copy, circa 55 pages. Published by the Huntington Library.
  - Roosevelt family. Correspondence and documents relating to the Roosevelt family. 1786-1846 12 pieces. (Box 10)
    Includes letters of and documents relating to James Isaac Roosevelt, between 1799 and 1842.
  - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882. Signed correspondence. Circa 1864-1870 3 items. Holograph. (Box 19)
    Letter to "My dear Gamburt," 1864 May 3. Letter to "Dear Inchbold," 1870? Thursday. Letter to "My dear Sir," 1869 November 15.+
  - Rothenstein, William, 1872-1945. Manuscript., n.d.; (4 items, 52pp. [holograph and typescript]). (Box 289, Folder 6)
    For chapter in A.E. Lawrence's T.E. Lawrence by His Friends. Comprises pp.287-293 (1937 edition).
    Gift of Majl Ewing, part purchase.
  - Routledge, firm, publishers, London. Correspondence. 1915 June 23 1 item. Typescript. (Box 17)
    1 letter to J. Gilmer signed by Laurie Magnus, Director of George Routledge and Sons, Ltd., 1902- 1933.
  - Russell, Bertrand, 3rd Earl Russell, 1872-1970. [Some prospects: cheerful and otherwise]. Circa 1928 22 leaves. 25.5 centimeters. Holograph. (Box 12)
    Ex libris: W. O. Schneider.